hello and welcome to all the positive
people watching this video this video is
going to be a little different because I
don't have a script I have some thoughts
in my mind and in my heart which I want
to share without any script as such
because the problem that a lot of
positive People Like Us face is that we
innocently think that everybody around
us whether in our home in our society or
in our office is as positive as we are
or is as good a well-wisher as we are
but the reality is something else in
reality
not everybody is your well vision
so we need to stop telling people
everything about our personal and
professional lives because believe it or
not a lot of people don't even care
and there are a specific set of people
who are actually secretly wanting you to
fail all right so we need to be very
cautious of what information we share
whether we share our career plans
whether we talk about some of our
vulnerabilities or our weaknesses or
whether we talk about some personal
incident which happened in our home we
need to be extremely cautious with whom
we are sharing this information and how
this information can be perceived and
how this information can be communicated
to other people and then used against us
okay and let me tell you few examples
there may be few people watching this
video who may be one or two years of
experience in the industry and are
planning to do MBA so while you are
doing your job you want to do MBA
full-time MBA you are probably preparing
for cat
or maybe a few people who have 8 to 10
years of experience who are thinking
that okay now I should
go ahead and probably do a Executive MBA
a lot of people have these thoughts and
what they do is very innocently over
lunch or you know just over tea or
coffee conversation they go and share
this information with their friends or
colleagues not just casual Chit Chat
that okay you know what I'm thinking to
do an Executive MBA or I'm planning to
crack CAD exam and I want to go into an
IIM etc etc so what happens is it is not
an issue that you are sharing this
information in confidence or because you
have trust over your friend or colleague
but the real issue is you don't know how
this information is now going to get
transmitted to other people
because this was a casual chat now this
friend of yours can go and share it with
other people now those other people can
talk about it add some gossip and it can
get shared with more people and
eventually it will reach your manager or
it will be somebody who is a decision
maker now as soon as that information
reaches them it may not reach with the
right sentiment it may not reached in
the way you communicated it it may be in
a very very different Manner and now
your manager or leader may not even talk
to you but he has found a perception and
that perception may be that this person
is planning to leave in the next few
months or years and as soon as they make
that perception all the decisions now
that they start to make about you with
respect to giving you some role with
respect to planning for your career
provision etc etc is done in that light
because now they know or have a thought
in their mind that you are going to go
and leave this company because you want
to do an MBA so this can be one way you
your manager May react or respond on the
other hand you may have a very positive
manager who may get to know this
information and then they may call you
and then they may have a dialogue with
you that okay you know what I heard this
is this true if this is true then how
can we retain you in the company maybe
give you some time off and then you can
go and pursue your MBA come back and
maybe we can give you a bigger role so
some people may perceive it in that
light as well which is a positive light
but generally when you casually share
any personal information any plan any
secrets weaknesses vulnerabilities then
there are high chances that it will get
spread and there are high chances that
it will create a negative impact so what
I want you guys to understand is please
be very cautious with what information
you share with whom do you share and be
aware of how this may be used by certain
people against you okay so that was
Point number one point number two is
understand that success is war about
your personal growth so if you're
getting success in a particular NBA War
it is about your personal growth which
means you learned a skill which means
you got a better pay which means you
found out or discovered some new area of
research which was not known to you
earlier so success is actually more
about your personal growth than it is
about public Applause so if you are
putting an extra hour to learn a new
skill then that is your core secret of
learning a new thing which you don't
probably need to go and tell to the
entire world it because not every step
in your career requires public
validation and we need to recognize that
not everyone is invested in our growth
so be selective with respect to whom you
want to share your success stories or
with whom do you really want to share
your plans and detailed insights should
be really shared with those who are
really invested in your Journeys and you
are pretty sure that these people are on
your side so don't go and share your
success stories or details of how you
got success just to gain Applause that
was Point number two point number three
is cherish genuine feedback there will
be so many people around you in your
home in your company in your Society or
Community who will continue to give you
feedback which means sometimes it will
be just criticism sometimes it will be
constructive criticism so you need to
seek feedback genuinely from mentors
peers and individuals who are genuinely
interested in your growth so when you
hear a lot of feedback you need to have
the common sense and ability to separate
a signal from a lot of noise so a signal
is something which you want to receive
but at the same time you want to push
away all the noise so your ability to
cherish genuine feedback is more
valuable than a hundred empty places
before I close I want to leave you with
this message every step you take no
matter how quiet actually shapes your
career Journey so let's prioritize
purpose and passion over public
perception wishing you the success
onwards and of words always let me know
your thoughts and comments I'll see you
in another video soon take care and bye
for now